This is pretty much
what's happened so far.
지금까지 얘기는 이래요
로스는 오랫동안
레이첼을 짝사랑했는데
Ross was in love
with Rachel since forever.
매번 사랑을 고백하려면
훼방꾼이 나타났죠
Every time he tried to tell her,
something got in the way...
...Iike cats, Italian guys.
고양이, 이탈리아 남자...
And finally, Chandler was,
like, "Forget about her."
결국 레이첼을 포기하고 말았죠
When Ross was in China, Chandler
let it slip that Ross loved Rachel.
한데 로스가 중국에 간 사이
챈들러가 로스의 맘을 털어놨고
She was, like, "Oh, my God!"
레이첼은 이랬죠
'세상에나! '
레이첼은 공항으로 로스를
마중 나갔는데
So she went to the airport to meet him.
She didn 't know Ross was getting
off the plane with another woman.
로스가 웬 여자와 돌아왔죠
거기까지만 아시면 돼요
That's pretty much everything
you need to know.
But enough about us.
How have you been?
저희 얘기는 그만두고
그간 잘지내셨어요?
The One With Ross' New Girlfriend
Flight number 457
from Beijing now arriving.
베이징발 457기가
도착했습니다
Oh, my God!
세상에나!
이걸 어째!
Excuse me.
실례, 긴급사태 발생!
비켜 줘요!
Move, move, move!
Emergency, please!
Excuse me, excuse me.
레이첼!
There you are!
거기 있었구나!
그래...
So, so....
중국 여행은 어땠어?
이 '친구'야!
How was China? You!
It was great.
아주 좋았어
- 거긴 왜 그래?
- 뭘?
What happened?
-You're bleeding.
-I am?
- 피가 나잖아
- 정말?
Oh, look at that! Yes, I am.
어머, 나 오늘 피 봤네
신경 쓸 것 없어
동양에서 돌아온 '친구'
Enough about me,
Mr. Back From The Orient!
Come on, I wanna hear everything!
Everything!
전부 다 말해 줘
하나도 빼놓지 말고!
Well, where do I start?
어떻게 말해야 할지
This is Julie.
Julie, this is Rachel.
여긴 줄리고
줄리, 이쪽은 레이첼
안녕하세요
참, 이 꽃다발은...
These are....
These are...
너 주려고 산 거 아냐
...aren't for you.
받으세요
These are for you.
Welcome to our country.
우리 나라에 잘 오셨어요
Thank you. I'm from New York.
고마워요
난 뉴욕 토박이예요
No problem. We'll use them
to stop the bleeding.
그렇다면 붕대 대용으로
쓰면 되죠 뭐
그건 그렇고...
짐 찾아야지?
Baggage claim?
- 그래
- 좋아
공항으로 마중 나갔어
로스랑 합치겠대
She went to the airport, and
she's gonna go for it with Ross.
Oh, my God! This is huge!
세상에, 이건 사건이야
사건보다 더 큰 사건...
그런 게 뭐가 있지?
This is bigger than huge.
This is....
All right, what's bigger than huge?
- 이 일?
- 그래
This?
Guys, you got new haircuts!
- 둘이 머리 잘랐어?
- 응, '비달 부페'가 했어
Yes, we did.
Thanks to Vidal Buffay.
'전문가의 손길을
느껴 보세요'
Because, you know, "lf you don't
look good, we don't look good."
I love that voice!
이 목소리 톤 정말 좋다
얘들아!
You guys!
Airport. Airport. Ross.
공항에서... 로스가...
혼자가 아냐
Not alone.
Julie.
줄리... 어깨에 손을 턱 걸치고
아이고 배야!
Arm around her!
Cramp! Cramp! Cramp!
I think she's trying
to tell us something.
뭔가 말하려는 것 같은데
Quick, get the verbs.
단어를 연결해 봐
You! You!
너! 너지! 로스가 날
좋아한다고 한 게 너지!
You said he liked me!
You!
You slowpokes!
너 말이야
왜 이렇게 느려?
That's all right.
We got the bags.
네가 가방을 버리고 가서
잘지냈어?
This is my sister, Monica.
내 동생 모니카야
챈들러
This is Chandler.
- 반갑다
- 그래
안녕, 피비
조이, 잘 있었어?
Phoebe, hi.
Joey.
Everyone, this is Julie.
다들 줄리하고 인사해
Julie.
여러분, 줄리예요!
- 안녕하세요!
- 잘 왔어요
반가워요
지금 모습은 잊어 줘요
But I'm not here,
you haven't met me.
I'll make a better impression when
I don't have 20 hours of plane on me.
20시간 비행기를 탔더니
꼴이 말이 아니거든요
- 버스도 탔어
- 맞아!
-And bus.
-Oh, my God!
- 악쓰던 사람 기억나?
- 침까지 뱉었잖아
-With the screaming guy
-And the spitting.
나중에 얘기해 줄게
You gotta hear this story.
낡아빠진 버스를 탔어요
We're on this bus
that's 200 years old.
- 한 200년 된 버스였어
- 한데 한 남자가...
Two hundred, at least.
And the chicken poops in her lap!
닭이 무릎에 똥 쌌대!
어머, 미안해
I'm so sorry.
I just gave away the ending, didn't l?
내가 다 말해 버린 거야?
I just heard this story in the cab...
차에서 이미 들어서
다 아는 얘기잖아
...and it is all I can think about.
This is amazing.
궁금한 게 있는데
어떻게 만났어?
How did this happen?
We were in grad school together.
우린 대학원 동창이에요
We haven't seen each other since then.
I land in China...
이후로 못 만났었는데
중국의 발굴팀 대장이
누구였는지 알아?
...guess who's in charge of the dig?
Julie!
줄리!
Isn't that great?
정말 대단한 인연이지?
Isn't that just kick-you-in-the-crotch,
spit-on-your-neck fantastic?
꼭 가랑이 걷어차고
침 뱉는 사이 같아!
좋다는 표현이에요
It's an expression.
We just wanted to say a quick hi.
잠시 인사하러 들렀는데
이제 아기 보러 갈 거야
-Then we'll see the baby.
-Then get some sleep.
- 잠도 좀 자고
- 중국은 지금 아침 6시거든
It's 6:00 tomorrow night, our time.
나도 중국에 갈 건데
미리 말하면 어떡해!
Don't tell us what's gonna happen.
I like being surprised.
Bye!
- 안녕
- 갈게
- 레이첼, 나 커피 줘
- 알았어
-Can I get some coffee?
-Sure.
- 고마워
- 난...
-Did you talk to him yet?
-No.
- 로스에게 얘기했어?
- 아직
그럼 주문하지 마
Then, no.
What the hell happened to you in China?
중국에서 어떻게 된 거야?
떠나기 전까지만 해도
넌 열렬했잖아
When last we left you,
you were in love with, you know.
I know I was.
알아
But there was always this voice
inside that kept saying:
한데 '너희는 절대 안 돼'란
소리가 들리더라고
"It's never gonna happen. Move on."
You know whose voice that was?
누구 목소리였는지 알아?
God?
신?
It was you, pal.
네 목소리였어
Maybe it was God doing me.
신께서 날 흉내냈구나
You were right. She looks at me
and sees a friend. That's all.
네가 옳았어
레이첼은 날 친구로만
생각한다고
And then I met Julie...
그리고 줄리를 만났는데...
...and we're having a great time.
우린 아주 잘 맞아
I never would have gone for it,
if it hadn't been for you.
다 네 덕분이지
Well, you owe me one, big guy.
나중에 신세 갚아
Your lemonade.
여기 레모네이드
I didn't order it.
난 안 시켰는데?
그럼 직접 가서 바꿔 와
돈은 네가 내는 거니까
Then go take that back.
They'll charge you for that.
- 하지만...
- 어서 가, 동작 봐라!
Go, go, go! Come on, come on!
좋아
뭐 좀 알아냈어?
So what did you find out?
He said....
로스가 말하길...
둘이 아주 잘 맞는대
They're having a great time.
I'm sorry.
- 미안해
- 뭐라고?
But the silver lining,
if you wanna see it...
그나마 다행인 건
자기 신념에 따라 결정했대
...is that he made this decision
all by himself...
...without any outside help whatsoever.
다른 사람의 입김은
완전히 배제하고!
How is that a silver lining?
그게 왜 다행이야?
You have to really wanna see it.
네가 꼭 알아야 하니까
아이러니하게 저 친구들은
운동신경이 아주 엉망이래
Ironically, these guys
were picked last in gym.
피비...
Hey, Pheebs.
You know what I'm thinking?
- 내가 무슨 생각하게?
- 알아!
How...
남자랑 관계를 가진 지
하도 오래돼서
...it's been so long
since you've had sex...
...you're wondering
if they've changed it?
방법을 다 까먹었다고?
No. Although now
that's what I'm thinking.
아니, 그러고 보니
그것도 그러네
무슨 일인데?
So what were you thinking?
You gave the guys great haircuts.
I thought you'd like to do mine.
남자들 머리 잘라 줬으니
내 머리도 잘라 줄래?
아... 싫어
No.
Why not?
- 왜?
- 그냥...
Because I'm just....
I'm incredibly anal and
an unbelievable control freak.
난 성격이 까다롭고
변덕부리기를 좋아하거든
넌 안 그래
No, you're not.
I know I'm not, but you are.
알아, 네가 그렇다고
감정이입을 해본 거야
I was trying to spare your feelings.
여보세요?
네, 안녕하세요
Hold on.
잠시만요
Ross, Julie for you.
로스, 줄리 전화야
응, 나야
- 누구 아는 양복점 있어?
- 옷 줄이게?
Anybody know a good tailor?
You need clothes altered?
아니, 그냥 몸 치수나 한번
재 보려고
No, I'm just looking for a man
to draw on me with chalk.
Go see Frankie. My family's
been going to him forever.
프랭키 씨네 가 봐
우리 집은 거기서만 해
He did my first suit when I was 1 5.
15살 때 내 첫 양복도
그 아저씨가 해줬어
아니, 16살 때였다
No, wait, 1 6.
No, excuse me, 1 5.
미안, 15살 때였어
All right, when was 1 990?
1990년에 내가 몇 살이었지?
귓밥은 귀가 아플 때까지
파면 안 돼, 알겠어?
You have to stop the Q-Tip
when there's resistance!
알았어, 자기야
나중에 봐
Sweetheart, I'll see you later.
Okay, bye.
알았어, 끊을게
뭐라고?
이렇게 고마울 데가!
That is so sweet.
아냐, 먼저 끊어
Okay. No, you hang up.
No, you
알았어
One, two, three.
하나, 둘, 셋!
You didn't hang up either.
자기도 안 끊었잖아
She didn't hang up.
- 줄리도...
- 전화를 안 끊었어!
아냐, 먼저 끊으라니까
자기가 끊어!
No, you hang up.
You. You.
Sorry, I thought
you were talking to me.
미안, 나한테 그런 줄 알았어
레이첼!
Rachel.
- 다시 걸어야겠어
- 맘대로
I'll just call her back.
전화가 갑자기 끊겼어
아냐, 먼저 끊어
Hi, sweetie. I'm sorry.
We got disconnected.
No, you hang up.
내가 왜 이렇게 됐지?
How did this happen to me?
A week ago, two weeks ago, I was fine.
2주일 전까지만 해도
난 로스를 거들떠도 안 봤는데
Ross was just Ross. Just this guy.
Now all of a sudden, he's Ross...
갑자기 로스가 다가갈 수도
없는 사람이 됐어!
...this really great guy
that I can't have.
Sweetie, I wanted you to have him too.
- 둘이 잘되길 바랬는데
- 알아
I know you did.
I'm just gonna deal with it.
태연하게 대처할 거야
I gotta get out of here!
정말 못 봐주겠다
뭔지는 몰라도
완전히 열받았나 봐
I don't care what you guys say,
something's bothering her.
16살 때였던 것 같아
You know, I think I was 1 6.
Please, just a little bit off the back.
부탁할게
뒷머리만 좀 잘라 줘
내 대답은 '싫어'야
I'm still on "no."
Morning.
좋은 아침!
잠깐 눈 좀 감아 줄래?
Could you close your eyes for a sec?
아니, 절대 못해
이번엔 안 속는다고
No, no, no. I'm not
falling for that again.
What's going on?
왜 그래?
I sort of did a stupid thing last night.
간밤에 멍청한 짓을 했거든
What stupid thing did you do?
무슨 멍청한 짓?
엄마야!
Why don't you just go get dressed...
어서 들어가서 옷 입고
나와요, 안녕!
...then you'll be on your way.
Bye-bye.
레이첼, 어떻게 된 거야?
How did this happen?
I kind of ran into him last night.
어젯밤에 만났어
-Where?
-At his apartment.
어디서?
저 사람 아파트에서
이거 주스야?
Is this juice?
And the fact that you dumped him
because he hit on Phoebe?
피비에게 치근댄다고
찰 땐 언제고?
Oh, God, I know.
I'm pathetic, I'm a loser.
알아, 난 정말 한심해!
Honey, you're not pathetic.
You're just sad.
한심한 게 아냐
상심해서 그런 거지
People do stupid things
when they're upset.
화가 나면 다들
어리석은 짓을 하잖아
My God, if I had a nickel
for every guy I wish I hadn't
남자랑 헤어질 때마다
내가 동전을 모았다면...
But this is about your horrible mistake.
네 문제나 논해 보자
안녕!
어서 와
어이...
Sorry we're late.
늦어서 미안해
좀 부비고 오느라고
We were....
Well, there was touching.
- 로스!
- 파울로!
Hey, Ross!
What a....
어떻게...
What are you doing here?
여긴 무슨 일이야?
I do Raquel!
라켈이랑 잤거든
So he's back?
- 둘이 다시 만나네
- 그래, 무슨 문제 있어?
Yeah, he's back.
Is that a problem?
No, not a problem.
- 아니, 전혀
- 그럼 다행이고
Good. Glad it's not a problem.
내 엉덩이에서 손떼요!
You're gonna have to not touch my ass.
베이글은 먹고 싶지만
분위기가 영 그렇네
Despite the yummy bagels
and palpable tension...
... my pants need to be altered.
난 바지 줄이러 갈래
프랭키 아저씨에게
안부 전해 줘
When you see Frankie,
tell him Joey Tribbiani says hello.
He'll know what it means.
무슨 뜻인지 알 거야
You sure he'll crack that code?
그가 정말 그 암호를
풀 수 있을까?
It's funny. The last time Paolo
was here, my hair was so much cuter.
전에 파울로 왔을 땐
내 머리가 짧고 예뻤지
All right.
좋아
조건이 있어
But you have to promise that you
will not be all controlly and bossy...
절대 모니카 티를 내서
이래라저래라하지 마
...and all Monica about it.
I promise.
- 약속할게
- 어디 보자
All right, let's see.
이 부분은 잘라내고
몇은 살려 줄게
Now, some of you are gonna get cut
and some of you aren't.
But I promise, none of you
will feel a thing.
아무 고통 없이 말야
약속할게
-That's it. I quit.
-What? I didn't say anything!
- 더는 못 참아, 관둘래
- 아무 말 안 했잖아
이건 사람을 신뢰하는
표정이 아니라고
But this isn't the face of
a person who trusts a person.
This is the face of
a person who, you know...
이건 사람을 영 못 믿는다는
얼굴이란 말야
...doesn't trust a person.
미안해, 피비
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's just a little shorter
than what we had discussed.
내가 부탁했던 것보다
훨씬 짧게 잘라서
Would you relax?
I know what I am doing.
걱정 붙들어 매!
내게 맡겨두란 말이야
This is how he wears it.
그 남자도 머리가
이렇단 말야
그 남자라니?
How who wears it?
Demi Moore.
데미 무어
데미 무어는 남자가 아냐
Demi Moore is not a "he."
'아서'와 '텐'에 출연한
남자란 말야
Well, he was a "he"
in Arthur and in 10.
그건 더들리 무어야!
That's Dudley Moore!
난 데미 무어처럼
잘라 달라고 했고!
I said I wanted it like Demi Moore!
Oh, my God!
맙소사!
Oh, God!
이걸 어째!
미안해! 미안해!
데미 무어가 누구지?
Oh, my God! I'm sorry!
Which one is Demi Moore?
'폭로', '은밀한 유혹'
'사랑과 영혼'에 나왔던 여자!
She's the actress that was in
Disclosure, Indecent Proposal, Ghost!
- 머리 참 예쁘게 나왔지
- 알아!
She's got gorgeous hair.
I know!
How long do you want the cuffs?
얼마나 길게 입을 건가?
At least as long as I have the pants.
입을 수 있을 때까지요
I just got that.
뭔 말인지 알겠어
좋아
이제 안쪽 솔기를 재지
Now we'll do your inseam.
How is she?
모니카는 어때?
It's too soon to tell.
아직 단정짓긴 일러
쉬고 있는데
좋은 징조인 것 같아
She's resting, which is a good sign.
How's the hair?
머리는 어때?
I'm not gonna lie to you.
It doesn't look good.
솔직히 말할게, 로스
엉망이야
한쪽만 쳐내서
자다 일어난 것 같아
I put a clip on one side, which seems
to have stopped the curling.
Can we see her?
들어가 봐도 될까?
Your hair looks too good.
It'd upset her.
네 멋진 머리를 보면
돌아버릴지도 몰라
로스, 네가 들어와
Ross, you come on in.
Well, how you doing?
- 넌 어때?
- 괜찮아
I'm okay.
영 아니구나?
That bad, huh?
왜?
Look, I can sense when women
are depressed and vulnerable.
난 직감으로 상처받은
여자를 알아본다고, 앉아 봐
It's one of my gifts.
Joey, when I saw him
get off that plane with her...
둘이 비행기에서 함께
내리는 걸 보는 순간
심장이 철렁 내려앉았어
...I really thought
I just hit rock bottom.
But today, it's like
there's rock bottom...
한데 오늘은 그 심장이
저쪽으로...
... 50 feet of crap...
떨어져나간 기분이야
...then me.
Tell Ross how you feel.
로스에게 솔직히 고백해
어떻게 그래?
줄리는 어쩌고?
Come on, how can I just tell him?
What about Julie?
줄리가 뭘?
겨우 2주 사귄 사이야
What about her? They've only
been going out for two weeks.
로스는 널 10년 동안
짝사랑했다고
Ross has been in love
with you for 10 years.
- 글쎄, 난 모르겠어
- 레이첼!
I don't know. I don't know.
I've been with my share of women.
난 많은 여자를 겪어 봤어
I've been with a lot
of people's share of women.
내 여자들은 아니었지만
핵심은 이거야
But the point is...
로스의 널 향한 마음은
누구보다도 강렬해
... I've never felt about anyone
the way Ross felt about you.
Really?
정말?
Yo, paisan!
야, 변태!
나랑 얘기 좀 하자
Can I talk to you for a sec?
네 재단사
천벌을 받을 사람이야!
Your tailor...
...is a very bad man!
What are you talking about?
- 프랭키가 뭘?
- 무슨 일이야?
Hey, what's going on?
조이의 재단사가...
Joey's tailor...
날 더듬었어
...took advantage of me.
뭐라고?
설마, 내 12년 단골집인데
No way! I've been going
to the guy for 1 2 years.
솔기를 잰다고 해놓고
손을 집어넣더니...
He said he was gonna do my inseam.
Then he ran his hand up my leg
and then there was definite
What?
뭐?
오므리는 거야
Cupping.
That's how they do pants!
원래 다 그런 거야!
First they go up one side,
they move it over.
먼저 한 쪽을 재고 나서
다른 쪽도 똑같이 재는 거야
Then they go up the other side,
move it back, then they do the rear.
다음엔 엉덩이 쪽이고
왜?
Ross, tell him. Isn't that
how a tailor measures pants?
원래 바지 치수
그렇게 잰다고 말해 줘라
Yes, yes, it is.
In prison!
맞아, 감옥에서는!
- 너 바보냐?
- 내가 뭘?
What's the matter with you?
What?
That's not?
원래 그런 거 아냐?
Oh, my God!
오 마이 갓!
메리 타일러 무어도
이것보단 나을 거야
Even Mary Tyler Moore
would've been better.
I like it.
좋기만 한데 뭐
십계의 한 장면 같아
I do. I think it's a 10!
고마워
내 머리가 그렇게 전해 달래
Thank you.
My hair is very amused.
살다 보면 별일 다 생겨
Come on, things could be worse.
뉴욕 시민이 원시인 되는 건
아무것도 아니지
You could "get caught between
the moon and New York City.
기분 나쁘겠지만
네 꼴이 지금 그래
I know it's crazy, but it's true."
Thank you.
고마워 죽겠네
난 갈게, 안녕
Well, I gotta go. Bye.
Bye, Rach!
- 안녕, 레이첼!
- 잠깐!가는 거야?
Wait, are you leaving?
That's what I meant by "bye."
'안녕'이란 게 원래
그런 뜻이잖아
Can I talk to you for a sec?
- 잠깐 얘기 좀 할래?
- 알았어
의사가 탈장검사를 하는 건?
When the doctor does
that hernia test....
그건 괜찮아
That's okay.
무슨 얘기?
What's going on?
Well, okay, first of all...
그러니까... 첫째로...
... Paolo and I are not back together.
파올로랑 다시 만나는 거 아냐
That was a stupid thing I did.
과거로 돌아갈 수 있다면
절대 하지 않았을 그런...
If I could go back in time
and do it again...
어리석은 짓이었지
...well, I wouldn't.
Second of all....
둘째로...
왜?
What?
네가 남자랑 헤어져서
내게 조언을 구하고는
Is this one of those things
where you break up with a guy...
내일 다시 그 남자와
합치게 되고
... I tell you what I think...
...and the next day
you get back together with him...
그럼 난 바보가 되는
그런 얘기야?
...and I look like
a complete idiot?
- 아냐, 절대 아냐
- 좋아
그 자식 나쁜 놈이야
Well, then, I think the guy's scum.
때려 주고 싶을 정도로
재수가 없다고
I hate him. I mean, I actually
I physically hate him.
옛날에도 그랬고
I always have.
그런 남자를 만나기엔
네가 너무 아까워
And you are way too good
to be with a guy like that.
Really?
정말?
You deserve to be with someone
who appreciates you...
널 아껴주는 남자를 만나
넌 유머감각이 넘치고
귀엽고 다정하고...
...and who gets how funny...
...and sweet and amazing...
...and adorable and sexy you are.
섹시하기까지 하잖아
You know? Someone who wakes up
every morning thinking:
아침에 일어나서는
'내가 레이첼과 사귀다니! '
"Oh, my God. I'm with Rachel!"
그런 남자를 만나라고
You know? Someone
who makes you feel good.
널 기쁘게 해주는 남자
내가 줄리에게 하듯이
Like the way I do with Julie.
두 번째는 뭐였어?
Was there a "second of all"?
아냐, 그게 다야
No, I think that was the whole "all."
I gotta go.
그럼 갈게
- 고마워
- 안녕
Thanks.
정말이라니까, 아빠!
No, I swear to God, Dad!
그렇게 치수 재는 게
아니래요!
That's not how they measure pants!
I was thinking of doing it shorter,
like Andie MacDowell's haircut.
앤디 맥도웰처럼
짧게 자르고 싶어요
- 내가 해줄게요
- 정말로요?
-Yeah, I could do that.
-Really?
- 지금 자를래요?
- 좋아요!
-You wanna do it now?
-Great!
- 좋아요
- 그래요
See you.
- 나중에 봐요
- 잘 가요
이번엔 확실히 해야지
I just wanna make
really sure this time.
Andie MacDowell is the girl from
Four Weddings and a Funeral, right?
'네 번의 결혼식과
한 번의 장례식'의 여배우지?
No.
아냐
아니, 그건 라디 맥다울이고
That's Roddy McDowall.
'혹성탈출'에 나온 남자배우가
앤디 맥도웰이야
Andie MacDowell is the guy
from Planet of the Apes.
맞다!
- 고마워
- 천만에
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.